the number one best collagen food that
no one's talking about. If you wanted to
take your collagen to the next level and
improve your skin, your joints, your
cartilage. When people typically think
about collagen, they think about bone
broth, pork rind, egg whites, and all of
those are great and you need to consume
that. Another thing about collagen is
that you do not get any collagen from
plants. If you are a vegan, you're not
going to get any collagen. To get your
collagen, it must come from an animal
source. When you see plant-based
collagen products, they're mainly
collagen supporting products like
vitamin C, maybe some minerals, things
like that. And it is true that you need
vitamin C for collagen to work. This is
why when someone has scurvy, a severe
vitamin C deficiency, they start getting
bleeding gums because the collagen in
their gums falls apart. The other thing
to know about collagen is that you don't
get a lot of collagen from meat, maybe 1
to 3%. And out of all your protein in
your body, collagen makes up 30% of all
that protein. So in other words, if
you're trying to get your collagen from
a steak, especially a tender steak
without much collagen, you need to go
outside your meat to get your collagen.
But meat does provide your protein, your
amino acids, which is different. As we
get older, even after the age of 25,
your collagen starts going down, down,
down, down. A person that is younger,
let's say they're 17 or 18 years old,
has the absolute best collagen. They
have joints that have cushions in them.
Their spine is super healthy. Another
really important of collagen is to
support your arteries because your
arteries should be elastic. When the
arteries lose collagen and become stiff,
you can get high blood pressure and
hardening of the arteries. But collagen
provides the scaffolding of your skin to
prevent sagging skin or wrinkles, things
like that. And collagen is also
important in your eyes and have the lens
be elastic to be able to uh change its
shape. When you consume a lot of junk
food, refined sugar, starches, seed
oils, your collagen really tanks even
faster than aging. Now, real quick,
there's different types of collagen for
different purposes. You have type one
collagen, type two, type three, type
five, and type 10 collagen. Type one and
type three come from fish skin, chicken
skin, and bone broth. And that type of
collagen will help your skin, your
bones, and your hair. It provides the
skin with elasticity to prevent the
sagging of the skin. Type two collagen
mainly comes from cartilage. For
example, if you're eating a chicken leg,
you can boil that and get the cartilage
from that. Type two can really support
your joints. Collagen type five and 10
can come from rare organ meats or the
membrane in eggs. And those two types of
collagen can help deep into the cellular
area as well as supporting the eyes. And
so this is why it's important to have a
variety of different types of foods.
Some people use a supplement that has a
variety and they might add vitamin C to
it. Now, let's talk about the absolute
highest quality source of collagen that
is rarely talked about, but can take
your health to the next level. It
contains GAGs. It makes up your joints,
your skin, your fashcia, and even your
cell membranes. And you can increase it
with exercise. But a lot of people don't
have enough of it because they eat the
wrong foods or they're just getting
older. All of the things I'm talking
about are in this one source of
collagen. And this source is 90%
collagen. Certain plastic surgeons would
use it to inject into the skin to help
make the skin look younger. But guess
what? You can eat it and get similar
effects. Did you guess what it is?
Rooster comb. That's that little red
crest that these roosters have in the
top of their heads. And little do people
know, it is a superfood on steroids.
You're probably not going to find it in
a US grocery store. You'd have to go to
a Chinese or a Filipino grocery store or
even find a local farmer that has
chickens. Maybe at the farmers market,
you can buy the rooster combs. Some
people might even buy this as a
supplement. But the point is for skin
health, for joint repair, for gut
healing, for osteoarthritis, rooster
comb provides the highest quality
collagen. If it's hard to find, you can
do plan B because there's a second one
on the list, and that would be chicken
feet. Chicken feet have a tremendous
amount of beneficial collagen. Not quite
at the level of the rooster comb, but
pretty close. And you can put in a stew,
you can boil it off and get the collagen
from it. Number three is fish skin.
Super beneficial. When I buy fish, I
always buy it with the skin and I eat
the skin. Especially salmon skin. I can
live on that stuff. Beef tendons are the
next one on the list. Then bone broth.
But again, I recommend uh doing a
variety of different types of collagen
uh foods and or supplements providing
support on the different parts of your
body, whether it's the joint, the skin,
the gut, or in your eyes. Thanks for
watching and I will see you in the next
video.
Hey, before you leave, I just wanted to
give you a little quick history on some
of the books that I wrote. This was one
of the first books called Dr. Burke Body
Shapes. It was my attempt at um writing
about body types. Uh what was very
interesting about this book is I
actually did all the images myself. Uh
don't ask me why. Um they look actually
not quite as professional as some of the
uh images that I have in the new book.
But anyway, this is my first attempt
right here called Dr. Burke's Body Shape
Diets. Uh and then I wrote a book um
more extensive called The Seven
Principles of Fat Burning. I don't even
have a copy anymore actually um because
it's outdated. Uh the next book uh I put
about a thousand hours into this one
right here called The New Body Type
Guide. Major updates on the body types.
Uh I put a lot of energy into this. Uh
it has professional images, graphics,
all sorts of things. Now, the problem
with this book is it doesn't really
describe what this is really about. Body
types are only a small portion of what's
in this book. And that's why I changed
the name to the healthy keto plan. Okay?
If you happen to have this book, you
don't really need this book because
there's some only very, very minor
updates. But if you don't have this, you
need to get this one right here. Um,
this book goes into every single detail
that you would ever want to know about.
It goes into the seven principles of fat
burning. goes into hormones, uh the body
types, the basic keto plan, it goes into
intermittent fasting. I talk about the
10 fat burning triggers and blockers and
fat burning strategies with a lot of
details in every single chapter. I go
into body issues that interfere with
losing weight. Um there's very few
people that just have a weight problem.
They have a lot of body issues, whether
it's sleeping problems, uh stress
problems, inflammation,
menopause. I cover that extensively in
this book. Then I talk about how to get
rid of stress and I show you a
technique. Uh then I get into exercising
and then I have a lot of really good
recipes in this book as well. So uh this
is a good reference guide um on my
website. If you get this book, you get
this one free. It's called Healthy Keto
Intermittent Fasting. This is the
shortcut uh quick guide to this book.
And uh the reason I created this book is
to have you within 45 minutes learn how
to do keto, okay, in intermittent
fasting, exactly what you need to do.
Then you can fill in the blanks with
this book right here. So right now I'm
doing a special. If you get this book,
you get this one totally free. Or you
can go to Amazon and get these
individually. So I just want to clarify
the difference between this book and
this updated one right here. If you
don't have this, you need to get this
right here. That way you can get the
exact correct information to do it
healthily.